想活命就跟我走
Come with me if you wanna live.
超 女
第五季 第十一集
你的糖果盘来了  夫人
Your candy tray awaits, milady.
各位  我很感激这顿分手盛宴  但我没事
Okay, guys. I appreciate the breakup feast, but I'm fine.
剥夺我们今晚敞开吃巧克力的权利  那可不行
And deny us a night of guilt-free chocolate? I don't think so.
真的  我觉得布莱尼和我分手很好
Really. I think it's good Brainy and I broke up.
是
Right.
我说的是实话  你看...
I'm being honest. Look...
布莱尼显然有些
Brainy clearly has some...
复杂的情感我没有察觉到
emotional complexities that I wasn't aware of.
不管那是不是性格抑制器的原因
And whether that's because of the personality inhibitors or not,
现在知道了总是比较好
it's better to know now.
要我说实话  我有点担心布莱尼
Well, I will be honest. I am a bit worried about Brainy.
是啊  那种感觉一定很奇怪
Yeah. I mean, it must be so strange
整个自身发生那么大的变化
to have your whole self just shift like that.
那么超查部那边怎么样了
So, how's it been at the DEO?
真不敢相信在这个宇宙里  它归于莱克斯旗下
Can't believe Lex owns it in this universe.
员工有股权和四个星期的带薪假期
Employees get stock options and four weeks paid vacation.
但没有任何假期能掩盖邪恶
But no beach vacation can mask evil.
真希望我们能知道他在筹划什么
Just wish we knew what he was up to.
你逃出来了
You're welcome
不必谢我
for the breakout,
顺便提一下
by the way.
我想着留着感谢的话
You know, I figured I would save my thanks
等听到你的提议之后再说
until after I heard your proposition.
你可真是有胆
That's a bold stance
毕竟你刚从另一个地球过来  多久来着
from a guy who got himself arrested, what,
十六个小时  就被抓起来了
16 hours after coming here from another Earth?
所以  我先假定你是无辜的
So, I'll give you the benefit of the doubt.
你还真是慷慨
Aw, that's very kind of you.
既然你那么了解我
And since you know so much about me,
为什么不告诉我你是谁呢
why don't you tell me who the hell you are?
我叫莱克斯·卢瑟
The name's Lex Luthor.
真是个怪名字
That's a weird name.
不比"玩具人"奇怪
No weirder than Toyman.
那是你父亲的名字  对吗
That was your father's name, wasn't it?
你需要把眼界放开
You need to think bigger.
就像你父亲一样
Like your dad.
他是要成为有史以来最大的玩具制造商
He was gonna be the biggest toymaker of all time.
刚进军虚拟现实  但是
Just moved into virtual reality, but,
他的搭档偷了他的专利  对吗
his partner stole his patent, right?
没错  然后他疯了
Right, and then he snapped.
人们说他进行了大屠杀
People say he went on a rampage.
我说  那是他们罪有应得
I say that they had it coming.
然后  他自杀了
And then, he killed himself.
你想让他们知道  他们错得有多离谱吗
Wouldn't you like to show them how wrong they were?
那正是我之前在做的
That's what I was doing.
你之前被逮住了
What you were doing was getting caught.
但是有了我的资源
But with my resources,
你可以让肖特这个名字与天才和混乱挂钩
you could make the Schott name synonymous with genius and chaos
而不是做个失败的无名氏
instead of failure and... who?
我有东西给你
I have something for you.
纳欣诺市玩具展
The National City Toy Convention.
还有个好消息  你的一位老朋友
And, as a bonus, I believe an old friend of yours,
切斯特·邓诺兹揭露新玩具
切斯特·邓诺兹  也会在那里
Chester Dunholtz, will be there.
很高兴和你做交易  温斯洛
Well, it has been a pleasure doing business with you, Winslow.
还有一件事
Oh, and one more thing,
不管你做什么
whatever you do,
闹大点
make it splashy.
如果我们想要留下遗产
If we're gonna build you a legacy,
那就需要它能影响到未来
it's gonna need to survive well into the future.
莉娜
Lena.
你正是我要找的卢瑟
Just the Luthor I was hoping to find.
你去我办公室找我了吗
Did you look for me in my office?
我说过会在那里研究"无害"计划  等着你
Where I said I would be, working on Non Nocere, waiting for you.
对了  不好意思  有突发状况
Ooh, right, sorry. Something came up.
这个新宇宙改变了Q波的频率
This new universe has shifted the frequency of Q-waves.
我回到了起点  我需要你的帮助
I'm back at square one. I needed your help.
我明白  但我们有个更大的问题
I understand, but we have bigger problems,
就像利维坦  你低估了他们  小莉娜
like Leviathan. You undersold them, sweet Lena.
他说得对
He's right.
利维坦是我们这个时代最大的威胁
Leviathan is the greatest threat of our time.
-布莱尼  -多克斯特工在帮助我完成计划
- Brainy. - Agent Dox is assisting me with a project.
你知道他是超女的朋友  对吧
You know he's friends with Supergirl, right?
没必要担心
There's no need for concern.
自从我移除性格抑制器后  我只听从逻辑
Since I removed my personality inhibitors, I run on logic only.
而我的计算告诉我  这一次  莱克斯·卢瑟
And my calculations tell me that, at this time, Lex Luthor
是站在历史上正确的一边
is on the right side of history.
你能向我保证  没有人会受伤吗
Can you promise me no one will get hurt?
我保证没有人会受伤
I promise no one will be harmed.
尤其是你能帮助我们的话
Especially if you help us.
就如同Q波
As with the Q-waves,
最近宇宙的融合可能改变了
the recent fusing of the universes might have shifted
安德里亚·罗哈斯对利维坦的认知
what Andrea Rojas knows about Leviathan.
如果有什么办法能
If there was some way of
-查清楚   -你想让我去和安德里亚谈谈
- finding out-- - You want me to talk to Andrea?
没有任何用  她什么都不会告诉我的
It won't do any good. She's not gonna tell me anything.
我们不是朋友
We're not friends.
我所认识的莉娜绝不会被友谊这种小事
The Lena I know wouldn't let a little thing like friendship
阻挡住她拯救世界的道路
get in the way of saving the world.
而作为感谢  我可以给你一个Q	波能量源
And as a thank you, I can guarantee you a source of Q-waves
明天之前送到
by the end of tomorrow.
如果你们不介意
Well, if you will excuse me,
我得去睡美容觉了
I have to get my beauty sleep.
他们明天会在纳欣诺市玩具展上
They're unveiling my new action figure
公开我的新人偶
at National City Toycon tomorrow.
应该会有很多人跟我合影
I anticipate many photo ops.
莱克斯·卢瑟
数量真多
There are so many.
我还以为会是值得收藏的珍品
I expected to be a collector's item.
卡拉·丹弗斯
Kara Danvers?
我是多么幸运
How did I get so lucky
凯特科会派他们的普利策奖得主
that CatCo would send their Pulitzer winner
来报道我这小玩意的揭露
to cover the unveiling of my little trinket?
我们才是幸运的一边  卢瑟先生
We are the lucky ones, Mr. Luthor.
这个新记者是谁
And who is this new cub reporter?
威廉·戴
William Dey.
我为《泰晤士报》报道了你对卡兹尼亚的胜利
I covered your Kasnian victory for The Times of London.
我记得那篇文章  你说我胖
I remember that piece. You called me fat.
那应该是自我膨胀
I believe it was bloated ego,
而且说的是你的胜利游行
and in reference to your victory parade.
没错  那场游行还不错
Oh, yes! That was a good parade.
超女没来真可惜
Oh, shame Supergirl couldn't make it.
你们的编辑肯定会喜欢买一送一
I bet your editor would have loved a twofer.
她是你的朋友  对吧
Say, she's a friend of yours, isn't she,
丹弗斯女士
Ms. Danvers?
超女会怎么看这些人偶
I mean, how would Supergirl feel about these action figures?
两位英雄拯救了世界
Two heroes saving the world.
要知道  我更关心你的看法  先生
You know what? I'm more interested in how you feel, sir.
简而言之
Uh, in a word,
英勇
valiant.
卢瑟先生  你打算把雪莱岛
Mr. Luthor, is it true you plan to develop
发展成能源来源是真的吗
Shelley Island as an energy source?
这颗星球陷入了能源危机
This planet is in an energy crisis.
我只是在出我的一份力
I'm just trying to do my part.
所以你打算接管罗杰斯工程公司
Is that why you attempted to take over Rogers Engineering?
你想进入生物力学领域
You wanted to get into biomechanics,
但罗素·罗杰斯不卖  还消失了
but Russell Rogers refused to sell, and he disappeared.
你不知道他遭遇了什么  对吧
You don't know what happened to him, do you?
没错
No.
采访很愉快
And this has been a delight.
我今天很忙
I have a very busy day.
不如送你一个我的人偶
Why don't you take one of these, on the house?
-丹弗斯女士  单独聊几句  -行  我马上回来
- Uh, Ms. Danvers, a quick word, please? - Yes, I'll be right back.
这本该是篇软文
This was supposed to be a puff piece.
我倒是被理想派问个措手不及
Why did I just get Frost/Nixoned by a Boy Scout?
我来到这个地球后
Since I have been on this Earth,
都在保护地球  服务人民
I have done nothing but protect and serve.
让我承担另一个地球上的莱克斯犯的罪
Judging me for the crimes of another Earth's Lex,
并不公平  对吧
well, that's not fair now, is it?
我会查明你正在超查部干什么
I'm gonna find out what you're doing at the DEO.
精神可嘉
So much moxie!
我说清楚了
Let me make myself clear.
如果那位小科学家决定曝光莱克斯
If young Woodward decides to proceed with his Lexpose,
那对他的健康非常不利  别声张
it will prove very, very dangerous for his health, off the record.
再见
Have a nice day.
卡拉·丹弗斯是超女
Kara Danvers is Supergirl.
给我
Give me that.
超女  玩具展上有名武装狙击手
Supergirl, there's an armed sniper at the toy convention.
-我就在现场  -很好  我们马上到
- I'm already there. - Great, we're almost there.
我来找他
I'll look for him.
我们得疏散人群  封锁这里
We need this place evacuated and locked down.
我们不想造成恐慌
We do not wanna cause a panic.
这东西感觉属于
Does this feel like...
玩具人
Like Toyman.
这是炸弹
They're bombs.
他有枪
He's got a gun!
在上面  在上面
Up there! Up there!
-那人看上去像  -温  怎么回事
- Wait, that looks just like-- - Winn! But how?
不
Oh, no!
什么
What?
温
Winn?
你在这干什么
What are you doing here?
救切斯特·邓诺兹和我的未来
Saving Chester Dunholtz and my future.
你看到玩具人了吗
Have you seen Toyman?
开枪的人  跟我撞脸的人
The shooter! The guy wearing my face!
交给我了
I've got him.
扫描中
快  快
Oh, come on, come on!
该死  布莱尼
Damn it. Brainy,
你帮我锁定纳欣诺市的所有交通摄像头
I need you to lock on to every traffic camera in National City,
一定要找到那家伙
and please, please find this guy.
温  等等  放松一会儿
Winn, stop. Okay, just breathe for a minute, okay?
我们会找到另一个你
We're gonna find the other you,
-阻止他伤害其他人  -我们总能办到
- and then we'll stop him before he hurts someone. - We always do.
-没错  -我回到这个时间点就为了抓他
- Yeah. - I came back to this moment to catch him.
本该如此
You should have.
布莱尼
Brainy.
他说得对  我本该找到他
He's right. I should've caught him.
他现在可能已经伤害别人了
By now he could've hurt someone,
如果真这样  你们不会明白的
and if he hurts someone, I don't think you understand.
我的人生就完了
My life is over.
一切  我会失去一切  我的妻女
Everything! I will lose everything. My wife, my daughter.
慢着
Wait.
你有妻子  孩子
You have a wife? And a kid?
天啊  没错
Oh, my God, yes. Yes. Uh...
这是我妻子  埃拉  玛丽四月就两岁了
That's my wife, Aila. Mary is gonna be two in April.
她们好美  我
They're beautiful. I...
见到你真好
It's so good to see you.
我还是挺想你的
I mean, I might've missed you,
-就一点点  -我也是
- like, just like a little bit. -Yeah, me too.
-就一点点  -我非常想你们
- But just... - Yeah, well, I missed you, like, a lot.
离开你们很难过
It was really hard leaving you guys.
所以怎么回事
So, what happened?
我刚把玛丽哄睡
Well, I'd just finished putting Mary to bed.
然后有人在敲我家大门
And then somebody's knocking on the front door,
我就希望别把孩子吵醒
and I'm thinking, please don't wake the baby up,
然后埃拉突然开始争吵
and then Aila is arguing, suddenly,
不知道跟谁  维护我
with whoever it is, defending me.
我跑下楼看怎么回事
So I run down there to see what's happening, and...
结果是时间警察
it's the time cops.
指控我
Accusing me of killing
在今天这个时候杀了切斯特·邓诺兹
Chester Dunholtz on this date, at this time.
但你没有
But you didn't do it.
我也是这么说的
I told them that.
但他们有我的DNA作为证据
But they had my DNA to prove it,
我猜想  这肯定是有
so I'm thinking, "Okay, this must be some type of,
二重身
you know, doppelganger
这个人跟我爸一样脑子发疯了
person with my father's sick, twisted brain.
如果这位玩具人杀人了
And now, if this Toyman kills someone,
我就再也见不到我的家人了
I will never see my family again.
他们会把我关进监狱  更糟的是影响时间线
They'll put me in jail, or worse, it's gonna affect the timeline.
我从一开始就遇不到埃拉
And I will have never met Aila.
也不会有我女儿了
Or my daughter.
好吧  我们
Okay, all right. We'll just... Okay.
肯定有线索  对吧
Well, there must be something, right? I mean...
这个人
okay, this person.
这个人被发现在邓诺兹身边
This person was found lurking near Dunholtz,
他们可能在合作
so maybe they were working together.
我们有他的面部  可以做识别吧  布莱尼
You know? I mean, we've got a face. Can we get an ID, Brainy?
行  我去超查部
Yeah, I'll, um, I'll go to the DEO
开始清理图像  识别身份并进行追踪
and start cleaning up the image to ID it, tracking it.
我也会把温的飞船放进超查部的机库里保管
I'll, uh, also put Winn's ship in the DEO hangar for safekeeping.
不行  我不要莱克斯靠近军团的飞船
No, no, no, I do not want the Legion ship anywhere near Lex.
我有办法
You know what? I've got an idea.
我会打电话给一个老朋友
I'll just have to call an old friend.
英雄莱克斯·卢瑟吗
Lex as in Lex Luthor, the hero?
你为什么不要他接近军团的飞船
Why would you not want the Legion ship near him?
莱克斯不是英雄
Lex is not a hero.
我们只能让荣恩给你快速说明
We're just gonna have J'onn just bring you up to speed
到底发生了什么事
on exactly what happened.
谢谢你今天来见我
Thank you for seeing me today.
我想要向你道歉
I wanted to apologize to you
你拿了我母亲的坠子后  我对你太过分了
for how I treated you after you took my mother's medallion.
都过去这么多年了
After all these years?
为什么现在道歉
Why now?
安德里亚  我知道利维坦的事
Andrea, I know about Leviathan.
莉娜
Lena...
我一直想向你解释一切
I wanted to explain everything to you for so long.
我知道利维坦有多危险
I know how dangerous Leviathan is
你肯定吓坏了
and how terrified you must've been.
我现在明白了你从来没想过要背叛我
And I understand now that you never wanted to betray me.
是的  太难了
No, it's been so hard.
我知道我必须保护你
I knew I had to protect you.
你知道了真相  我真是松了一口气
I'm so relieved that you know the truth.
我也是
So am I.
利维坦叫你去做的任何事
And anything Leviathan has asked you to do,
我们都会一起想办法应对的
we will figure it out together.
他们从来没叫我做任何事
They've never asked me to do anything.
这么多年来  一句话也没有吗
All these years, and not a word?
他们说会打给我  但一直没出现过
They said they would call on me, but they never came.
很对不起
I'm so sorry.
你和我又在一起了
It's you and me again, okay?
我会陪你一起赴汤蹈火
You jump, I jump.
如果利维坦打给你  你就来找我好吗
If Leviathan calls you, you come to me, okay?
我不能再失去你
I can't lose you again.
好的
Okay.
安德里亚什么也不知道
Andrea knows nothing.
看来在这个地球上  在危机之后
Seems on this Earth, post-Crisis,
利维坦还没有激活她的能力
Leviathan hasn't activated her yet.
但是别担心  如果他们激活了她
But don't worry, if they do,
她会第一时间打给我
I'll be the first person she calls.
荣恩
J'onn?
我们来了
We're here.
很不错嘛  很有山姆·史贝德的范儿
Oh, this is nice! Very Sam Spade.
美国影片《马耳他之鹰》中的侦探
没想到荣恩是个如此热衷的读者
Never realized J'onn was such an avid reader.
他人呢
Where is he?
我在上面
I'm up here.
那是秘密电梯吗
Is that a secret elevator?
别推我
Don't push.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
一会告诉你们  首先
In a minute. First...
很对不起
I am so sorry.
但我们会找另一个你  并阻止他的
But we will find this other you and stop him.
你的拥抱总是很温暖  熊爸爸
Yeah. You always give the best hugs, papa bear.
荣恩  只是...
Okay, J'onn. Just...
-你要给我们说说这个地方  -是的
- You gotta tell us about this place. - Yeah!
在危机之后  卡拉  卡·艾尔
Well, in the wake of Crisis, Kara, Kal-El,
巴里  凯特
Barry, Kate,
我们建立了一个打击犯罪的总部
we established a headquarters from which to fight crime.
在未来  他们把它叫做正义大厅
Oh, in the future they call it a Hall of Justice.
我喜欢
I like that.
我想既然超查部现在隶属于卢瑟公司
I thought since Luthor Corp now owns the DEO,
纳欣诺市也许需要有自己的集体服务
National City could use its own collective.
保卫这个城市安全的总部
A headquarters to keep this city safe.
在公司和政府监管之外行动
To work outside of corporate and government oversight.
他们的利益也许有时会与正义有冲突
Whose interests might not always side with justice.
-就像尖端科研实验室  -或是绿箭地堡
- So, like S.T.A.R. Labs? - Or the Arrow bunker.
一个我的超级朋友能作战的地方
Place for my super friends to work,
只要有需要随时都能用
whenever they should need it.
你打算叫它什么呢
What are you gonna call this?
我在想叫它做高塔
I was thinking The Tower.
-太好了  -绝对是
- Cool! - Absolutely.
和我说说我错过的这场危机吧
So, tell me what I missed with this whole Crisis thing.
不告诉你
Not tell you.
给你看
Show you.
但我必须警告你
But I must warn you.
过去地球的真相还挺令人难过的
The truth of the old Earth could be quite upsetting.
不会比我现在要面对的更让人沮丧
Uh, not more upsetting than what I'm already dealing with,
所以能有多糟糕呢
so how bad can it be?
吐吧
Okay, get it out.
吐出来吧  没事了
Get it all out. It's okay.
莉娜杀了莱克斯吗
So, wait, Lena killed Lex?
然后他死而复生了吗
And then he came back to life?
詹姆斯经营一家小镇报纸  还辅导小孩子吗
And James runs a small town newspaper and mentors children?
太有爱了
That's-- that's adorable!
-还有你  你以前是俄罗斯人吗  -什么
- And you! You were, what, you were R-Russian? - What?
是的  卡兹尼亚  但那不是真实的我
Yes. Kasnian. But that wasn't really me.
所以超查部变成大坏蛋莱克斯的了吗
And so evil Lex now owns the DEO?
是的
Yeah.
但是让我跟你说说从虫洞过来的
Oh, but let me tell you about the doppelgangers
二重身
who came through a wormhole--
照片不错嘛
Not a bad picture of you.
我不明白
I don't understand.
在我的每一次模拟中  我们都抓到了玩具人
In every simulation I ran, we always apprehended Toyman.
他从未逃脱过
He never got away.
我不明白的是为什么你来了
What I don't understand is why you're here
但是军团飞船却没来
and the Legion ship is not.
丹弗斯局长认为把飞船
Director Danvers thought it would be safer to secure the ship
安置在纳欣诺市边界以南
at a government black site
4.8公里处的政府秘密据点  会更安全
three miles south of the National City border.
谢谢你  我到了那里之后
Thank you. And once I get there,
我怎样才能获取飞船对利维坦了解的内容
how do I access what the ship knows about Leviathan?
右象限角处有个仪表板
There is a panel on the right quadrant.
你从温·肖特的头发里找到了他的DNA
You have Winn Schott's DNA from his hair.
这就可以了
That's all you'll need.
我们的任务结束了
Now, our mission is over.
终止玩具人计划
Call off Toyman.
他看起来像是我的私人警犭吗
Does he look like my personal attack dog?
他藏起来了  玩具仔比我们想象的要聪明
He's underground. Toyboy is smarter than we gave him credit for.
玩具人会再次出手的
Toyman will strike again.
那就和你那帮好心的家伙一起
Then get out there with your little do-good crew
去搞定他
and take care of it.
纳欣诺市民  你们好
Hello, National City!
现在你们也许已经听说我在玩具展的精彩表演
Well, by now you might've heard that my splashy show at Toycon
引起了一点骚动
caused, well, a little bit of ruckus.
荣恩  你能找到他的位置吗
J'onn, can you track his location?
他屏蔽了IP地址和信号源
He's blocked his IP address and signal.
不管他在用什么技术
Whatever technology he's using,
绝对是我没见过的
it's something that I've never seen before.
而我已经想好了更大的计划
And I have got a bigger bang in mind.
告诉我  你是否被命运的不公待遇
Now, tell me. Have you ever been
激怒到甚至想要将一切
so unfairly wronged that it just made you wanna
焚烧殆尽
burn it all down?
我有过
Well, I have.
而我非常愤怒
And I'm angry.
有人伤害了我的家人
Someone hurt my family
还毁掉了我父亲的名声
and they destroyed my father's good name.
快看
Look at that.
有人在支持他
People are supporting him.
-他的粉丝在增加  -所以
- He's collecting followers. - So,
我有了目标  有了方法  我现在需要的
I have the target, I have the method, and what I need now...
就是你
is you.
给我力量
Give me the will.
给我点赞  订阅  分享  关注
Like me, subscribe, share, follow me,
等我拥有了一百万粉丝
and once I reach one million followers,
你们将看到前所未有的烟火表演
you will see a fireworks display like never before.
一起向胜利冲锋
So, let's play to win!
下次见
Until next time.
我就是
I am hashtag
#玩具人
Toyman.
各位
Guys?
1200万美元悬赏捉拿温·肖特
如果他赢了  我就死了
If he wins, I'm dead.
#玩具人  实时评论
没想到这么多人都支持暴力
I can't believe all these people are rooting for violence.
我一直在等这个  #玩具人
在网络匿名的掩护下
Well, the anonymity of the internet
大家最原始的直觉都觉醒了
brings out everyone's basest instincts.
可是如果那些人被针对  那他们又会如何
Sure, but how would those people feel if they were the target?
不幸的是  这就是21世纪的问题
Unfortunately, this is a distinctly 21st century problem.
到2126年
By, what, 2126,
全球反网络暴力法令施行
anti-trolling legislations are in place around the world.
阻止了第三次世界大战
Stopped World War Three.
我不该告诉你们这些的
I should not have told you that. Whoa.
我去搜查全城了
I'll go sweep the city.
看看现实世界里有什么线索
See what I can find in the real world.
需要我的话  给我打电话
If you need me, just call.
荣恩  太天才了
J'onn, that's genius!
丹弗斯局长  我接到你的电话了
Director Danvers, I got your call.
这里确实厉害
Yes, this place is genius.
布莱尼  你在这里我很开心
Brainy, I'm glad that you're here.
玩具人似乎在使用来自他世界的
Look, the Toyman is using some sort of IP address blocker
某种IP地址屏蔽器
from his world,
-而我们...   -我知道
- and we just can't-- - I know.
我一直想从超查部追踪他
I've been trying to track him from the DEO.
从那张照片里
Have you had any luck
能否查清玩具人的共犯
identifying Toyman's accomplice from that image?
那张照片太模糊  无法看清人脸
The image was too obscure to get a clear ID.
我们在军团飞船上也许有技术
Well, we might have something on board the Legion ship
能够提升图像质量
that can help enhance the image--
我说了我来处理
I said I'd do it.
我会处理
And I will.
安德里亚需要我  我得去凯特科
Andrea needs me. I have to go to CatCo.
有情况我会联系你
I'll call you if anything pops.
卡拉
Kara.
我觉得莱克斯和玩具人之间有关联
I think there's a connection between Lex and Toyman.
其实
Actually, yeah. Um,
我想跟你聊聊这件事
I need to talk to you about that--
超查部把玩具展控制起来的时候
When the DEO put Toycon on lockdown,
莱克斯出现了疏漏
Lex had just slipped up.
我相信莱克斯不止是他表现出来的样子
Okay, I believe that Lex is not who he says he is.
但是
But...
这也就是说我们必须聪明点
that means we have to be smart,
因为如果他很危险的话
because if he's dangerous,
我们不能进行没有根据的指控
we can't just go around making baseless accusations--
卡拉  我们是记者  无论风险多大都要追寻真相
Kara, we're reporters. We dig into hunches, no matter the risk.
卡拉
Kara.
我通知你开会的时候
When I call you in for a meeting,
你要直接来找我
I expect you to come directly to me.
威廉  我需要你今天陪着我
William, I need you with me today.
我父亲的母校要表彰我们全家
My father's alma mater is honoring the family
感谢我们在技术和娱乐方面的贡献
for our advancement in tech and entertainment.
我要在现场宣布下一代的黑曜石VR
I'm going to announce the next phase of Obsidian VR at the event.
白金黑曜石将是没人见过的经典
Obsidian Platinum will be like nothing anyone has ever seen before.
威廉  我希望你来报道
William, I want you to cover it.
-我不愿意  -真是好主意
- I'd rather not-- - That's a great idea.
-谢谢你  卡拉  -这想法很好
- Thank you, Kara. - It's a good idea.
我也有很特别的东西给你
And I have something special for you too.
好
Okay.
温·肖特在凯特科任职的时候  你跟他是朋友
You were friends with Winn Schott when he worked for CatCo,
他两年前消失了  对吧
before disappearing two years ago, right?
对
Yes.
你应该没想到他会在如此的邪恶丑闻中出现吧
Bet you never thought he'd reappear with such an evil splash.
我想要独家新闻  立刻就要
I'd like an exclusive. Immediately.
不
No!
抱歉  不行  我了解的温·肖特不是这样
I'm sorry. No! That is not the Winn Schott I know,
我也不会给一个疯子提供平台
and I will not give a platform to a madman.
玩具人已经有平台了
Toyman already has a platform.
他的视频能够在一小时内传遍五大洲
His video went viral across five continents in under an hour.
我们必须将这种热度利用起来
We have to capitalize on that kind of traffic.
我们不需要为了你的收入
We don't have to promote bloodshed
推崇暴力
for the sake of your bottom line.
其实  你的工资条告诉我们
Actually, according to your paycheck,
你需要
yes, you do.
威廉  你半小时内准备好
William, be ready in an hour.
卡拉
Kara,
给我把独家拿到
get me that exclusive.
你应该看看我的样子  父亲
You should see me now, Father.
在我们的地球上  他们称你为疯子  但是这里
Ha! On our Earth, they called you a psychopath, but here,
他们为我欢呼
they cheer for me.
也许这对你来说为时已晚  父亲  但是
And yes, it may be too late for you, Father, but soon
我很快就能实现你没做到的
I will accomplish what you could not.
你一直以来梦寐以求的
What you always dreamed of.
我会永生
I will live forever.
等等  这就是我一直以来等待的超级英雄总部
Wait, this is the superhero-level stuff I have been waiting for.
等等  尼娅  过来
Wait, Nia, Nia, wait, come here.
抱歉
Sorry.
温  这是尼娅
Winn, this is Nia.
-你好  -尼娅
- Hello. - Whoa, Nia.
是尼娅·纳尔吗
As in Nia Nal?
对
Yeah?
不可思议  天...
This is incredible. Holy...
-你好  -你的重重重重重...
- Hi. - I'm sorry, your great, great, great, great, great...
重孙女
bunch of greats granddaughter,
努拉·纳尔是我最好的朋友之一
Nura Nal, is, like, one of my best friends
也是最强的军团成员之一
and, like, the most kick-ass Legionnaire.
好夸张  跟我说说
That's crazy. Tell me everything.
她长得像我吗
Does she look like me?
等下
Okay, wait.
等抓到坏蛋再慢慢讲吧
Let's save story time until after we catch the bad guy.
好啊  乐意效劳
Right. Well, anything to help.
好
Okay.
他说粉丝突破一百万时就会出击
Once he's hit a million followers, he's promised to strike.
所以动作得快点
So, you'll have to work fast.
让她来
She can do it.
好  有什么标记
Um, right. So, are there any markers,
或者具体的东西需要我监视的吗
any specifics I can keep an eye out for?
我们只知道  他想要关注
All we know is that he wants attention.
关注  好
Attention. Okay.
不是你  滚出我脑袋  混蛋
Not you. Get out of my head, jerk.
没事
It's okay.
-没事  -抱歉
- It's okay. - I'm sorry.
你看到了什么
What did you see?
-什么都没  -什么都没吗
- Nothing. - Literally nothing?
不太可能吧
That seems unlikely.
好吧
Fine.
我看见一只老虎
I saw a tiger.
野猫
Wildcat.
我过去
Um, let me.
抱歉  帮不了你
I'm sorry I couldn't help you.
只是...
It's just...
我最近脑子有点乱
my mind's been a little messy lately.
没事
It's okay.
你能告诉我到底看到什么了吗
Do you mind telling me exactly what you did see?
努拉教过我解梦
It's just that Nura taught me how to interpret dreams.
我就像她身边的华生一样
I'm kinda like her Watson.
我看见我前男友变成老虎来攻击我
I saw my ex-boyfriend turn into a tiger and attack me.
野猫是我给布莱尼的昵称
Wildcat was my nickname for Brainy.
知道了
Oh, I know.
我以为我已经不会再想起他了
I just thought I was better than letting him get in my head.
我不能跟你说太多未来的事
You know, I can't tell you a whole lot about the future,
但我可以告诉你
but I can tell you
你
that you,
尼娅
Nia,
是个强大的女人
are a powerful woman.
你看这个
You see this?
我是军团里唯一的人类
So, I'm the only human Legionnaire,
所以我拿到军团戒指的时候
so when I got my Legion ring,
他们得用某种力量对它进行改造
they had to soup it up with, like, some cool powers.
-是梦境能量吗  -对
- Is that dream energy? - Yeah.
努拉和我利用她和你的力量设计出了
So, Nura and I, we fashioned the ring's abilities after her and
戒指的能力
your powers.
千万不要受人影响
Never let anyone
怀疑自己的价值
make you question your own worth.
好的
Okay.
这句话的专利是努拉·纳尔的
And that is patented Nura Nal advice.
我要是不加这一句她能杀了我
She would kill me if I didn't give her credit.
谢谢  温
Thanks, Winn.
-你说得对  -我知道
- You're right. - I know.
我会再试一遍
I'm gonna try again.
你肯定是个好爸爸
You must be such a great dad.
我尽力
I try.
这是我做过最难的事了
It's, like, the hardest thing that I have ever done.
-我想也是  -没开玩笑
- I bet. - I'm not kidding.
当了爸爸后  我的心突然就...
Yes, it's like, I became a dad, and suddenly my heart was just...
敞开了  你明白吗
on the outside of my body. You know?
她是我最大的成就  小玛丽
She's also my greatest accomplishment, my little Mary.
她是我的宝贝
She's my legacy.
她的名字是来自你妈妈吗
Did you name her after your mom?
不叫这个  就叫威妮弗蕾德了
Well, it was either that or Winifred.
还想过叫卡拉
Kara was an option.
-什么  -真的  埃拉想起这个名
- What? - Yeah, Aila pushed for it.
不过说实话
But if I'm being honest, um,
在未来  卡拉这名字已经不能算作
in the future, Kara isn't exactly what you would call
是原创的名字了
an original name choice.
什么意思
What are you talking about?
很多家长以传奇人物卡拉·佐-艾尔给孩子起名
Parents naming their children after the legendary Kara Zor-El.
天啊
Oh, my gosh.
还是玛丽好听
No, I like Mary.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
而且  我暂时对自己的传奇不感兴趣
Besides, I'm not too hot on my own legend right now.
莱克斯威胁要杀我同事
Lex threatened to kill one of my co-workers
如果我不阻止他调查莱克斯的话
if I don't stop him from investigating Lex.
所以  我要么违背记者的职业道德
So, either I go against my journalistic ethics or...
要么得置威廉于险境
or I put William in danger.
我不知道怎么跟你说
Don't know how to tell you this,
但你每天都置我于险境
but you put me in danger, like, every day.
-不不不  别这么说  -真的
- No, no, don't say that. - No, you did.
你听我说  没事  没关系
No, listen, it doesn't matter. It doesn't matter though.
这是因为我知道  你总是会保护我
Because I knew that you were always gonna be there to protect me.
你是超女
You're Supergirl.
待在你身边  让人...
Being in your orbit, it's...
很受鼓舞
inspiring.
我怎么早没想到
Oh, why didn't I think of this before?
玩具人
Toyman!
他说他正为父亲倾尽一切
He said that he is doing everything for his father.
可他父亲并不在这个地球上
But his father didn't exist on this Earth.
但我父亲在
But mine did.
所以  如果我要受到父亲的鼓舞
And so, if I was gonna go be inspired by my father,
我会在哪工作呢
where would I work?
太迟了  如果玩具人来过  现在也走了
We're too late. If Toyman was here, he's gone now.
各位
Guys.
我好像有发现
I think I found something.
安德里亚和她父亲
Andrea and her father?
超能力家族
我父亲也有这种公告板  对付邓诺兹
My dad had a board just like this for Dunholtz.
那么在玩具人的地球上  罗哈斯肯定
So, on Toyman's Earth, the Rojases must've had something to do
和老温斯洛·肖特的落败有关
with the fall of Winslow Schott, Sr.
我们得去凯特科  提醒安德里亚
We have to get to CatCo. We have to warn Andrea.
她不在凯特科  她在...
She's not at CatCo. She's at...
纳欣诺市大学  跟威廉一起
National City University with William.
老虎之乡
Home of the Tigers.
哈里森堡
你真帅啊
Aren't you handsome?
我们现在相互联系  是吗
We're connected now, aren't we?
完全没错
Precisely.
我现在和你的意识有直接联系
I'm now directly linked to your consciousness.
那么你知道我想要什么
Then you know what I want.
把它给我
Give it to me.
等等
Hold.
放大
Enhance.
我见过你
I know you.
我怎么会见过你
How do I know you?
搜索这个女人
Search for this woman.
黑曜石之北创下盈利记录
当然
Of course.
在黑曜石
At Obsidian,
我们以声誉为赌注将科技推向前沿
we staked our reputation on pushing technology to the limits.
想象一个世界
Imagine a world
当你下班回家后
where, after you've come back from work,
你带上了黑曜石白金隐形眼镜  瞬间
you slip on your Obsidian Platinum contact lenses, and suddenly
你来到了托斯卡纳别墅  被美丽的葡萄园包围
you're on a Tuscan villa, surrounded by your beautiful vineyard.
你在阳台上摆了一张大餐桌
You set a large family table out on your verandah
喝着自己冠名的葡萄酒
where you let the wine from your own label flow.
之后你还可以从酒厂封装葡萄酒
Later, you can bottle the wine from your vineyard
并出售
and sell it for real money.
有了黑曜石白金
With Obsidian Platinum,
你再也不用在
you will never again have to choose
生活和梦想中选择
between your life and your dream.
你永远能两全其美
You can always have both.
笑一个
Smile!
猫咪二号
Kitty number two!
威尔  你在哪里
Will, where are you?
看到他了
I got him!
我的能力能这么用
My powers can do that?
去追玩具人  我能行
Go after Toyman. I've got this.
来吧  小猫咪
Here, kitty, kitty cat.
你想驯服机械老虎吗
Are you trying to tame a robot tiger?
如果椅子大小合适
If the chair fits.
住手
Stop!
谁说的
Says who?
你从哪里来的
Whoa, where did you come from?
另一个地球
Yet another Earth?
其实不是
Actually, no,
这是我的地球
this is my Earth.
这是我的生活  而你却搞砸了
This is my life, and you are really messing it up.
给我引爆器
Give me the trigger.
这就不好玩了
Uh, well, that would be no fun.
炸弹在面包车里吗
Is the bomb in the van?
听我说
Listen to me,
我知道想要保护家人的感觉
I know what it feels like to wanna protect your family.
相信我  我理解
Believe me, I do.
但你也要创造属于自己的传承
But you have also got to create your own legacy.
这就是我的传承
This is my legacy.
你看到其他人了  他们崇拜我
You've seen the people. They adore me.
兄弟  这不是喜欢
Dude, this isn't love.
不是的  你对他们来说只是廉价趣味
No, you're just a cheap thrill for them, all right?
把引爆器给我
Give me, give me the trigger.
不行  这可是给我这个将死之人的引爆器
Can't. It's a dead man's switch for a dead man, like me.
别再说了  你还能改变
Just stop that. You could still change.
好吗  你不是玩具人
All right? You are not Toyman.
你这么轻蔑地说着
You say that name Toyman
玩具人的名字  但你却不理解
with such disdain, but you, you do not understand.
玩具人是永恒的
Toyman is eternal.
纳欣诺市大学
你看见威廉了吗
Have you seen William?
他应该在这里的
He was supposed to be here.
我进行了分析
I ran diagnostics.
玩具人的袭击没有造成平民伤亡
We lost no civilian lives to any of Toyman's attacks.
这是好消息
Well, that's good news.
说到消息  我想知道未来的消息怎么样了
Speaking of news, I wonder what the news is like in the future.
结束了
It's all over.
你看过通缉令了吗
Have you looked at the wanted poster?
不见了
It's gone.
我知道
I know.
威尔  你在哪里
Will, where are you?
你不会相信我看到了什么
You're not gonna believe what I saw.
你本该在大学里  但你不在
You were supposed to be at the university, and you weren't.
我知道这件事情对你来说有多重要
I know how important this story is to you,
你不会让任何东西妨碍你
and that you won't let anything stand in the way of
追逐真相  即使是我
you getting it, even me,
但我还知道莱克斯会杀人的
but I also know that Lex would sooner take someone out
就为了不公布抹黑他的头条新闻
than let a headline be run that threatens his reputation.
-我没有想  -所以我在想
- And I'm not-- - Which is why I have been thinking,
我们应该一起调查莱克斯
we should investigate Lex together.
人多更安全
There's safety in numbers and...
如果我们共享消息
and if we share information,
我们有更好的机会彻底揭发他
we have a better chance at exposing him, once and for all.
你是说我们会像
You mean we'd be like...
-搭档  -没错
- partners? - Exactly!
是的  相互支持的搭档
Yes, who would have each other's back.
好的
Well then,
搭档
partner,
我觉得你应该看看这个
I think you need to see this.
我姐姐给我看过这个停机库
My sister showed me this hangar before,
这是政府高度机密  莱克斯怎么进去的
it's high government security. How did-- Lex get in?
他收买了警卫
He paid off the guards.
他有个计划  我们需要查明是什么
He's got a plan. And we need to find out what it is.
他没看见你  对吧
Well, he didn't see you, did he?
-当然没有  -那就好
- Of course not. - Good.
我很小心
I was careful.
那你想看看我剩下的笔记吗
So, do you wanna take a look at the rest of my notes?
天啊  对不起  现在太晚了
Oh, gosh, I'm sorry. I totally forgot what time it is.
我得走了
I have to go.
-重大日子  -最重大  今晚是游戏之夜
- Big date? - The biggest! It's game night.
你应该来参加
You should come.
不了
Uh, nah.
我不擅长游戏
You know, I'm not very good at games.
那不重要  这是
That doesn't matter, it's--
-再说  我还要吃晚餐  -不
- Besides, I have dinner waiting for me, so-- - No!
不管怎样  我都不会让你待在这吃那东西
Under no circumstances will I let you stay here and eat that...
这是我见过最凄惨的三明治
Well, that's the saddest sandwich I've ever seen.
走吧
Come on.
-不  扔了吧  -好的
- No! That stays. - Okay.
没有你可以参加的游戏之夜吗
Is there not a game night that you should be attending?
有的
Oh, there is.
但如果没有我棋盘问答的搭档
But I don't really stand much of a chance
我的胜算不大
without my Trivial Pursuit partner.
很遗憾  我不能参加
Sadly, I cannot partake.
荣恩让我升级诊断系统
J'onn has asked me to upgrade the diagnostic system.
不  他没有
No, he didn't.
布莱尼
Brainy.
你这是怎么了
What is going on?
兄弟  当老虎攻击时
Dude, I saw the way that you looked at Nia,
我看到你看尼娅的眼神了
when the tigers attacked.
那种失去爱人的恐惧
That fear of losing someone that you love.
自打我参与了这个  我脸上就一直有这种表情
I've had that same look on my face since I got to this time.
所以  告诉我真相
So, tell me the truth.
我
I...
欺骗了
have lied...
所有人
to everyone...
因为我
because I'd...
我必须和莱克斯·卢瑟合作
I've had to work with Lex Luthor.
为了拯救未来
I helped Lex bring you back
我帮助莱克斯把你带了回来
for the sake of the future.
-那是你吗  你  -温
- That was you? You-- - Winn--
-不不  你拿我的生命冒险  -我
- No, no, you risked my life. - I...
-布莱尼  我的家人  -我不得不  我
- Brainy, my family! - I had to, I...
莱克斯必须从你飞船中的
It was imperative that Lex get information
记忆魔方里获取信息
from the memory cube on your ship.
我计算过了
I did the calculations.
我知道没人会死
I knew no one would die.
我们会抓住玩具人
That we would catch Toyman, the...
我唯一没考虑到的就是莱克斯本人
The one thing I didn't account for was Lex himself.
他  他就是混乱的化身
He's, he's... chaos incarnate.
他完全不按常理出牌  我
He's completely unpredictable, and I...
我不知道我能否控制他
I don't know if I can control him.
温  我
Winn, I...
我非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
另一个布莱尼亚克告诉我必须
Another Brainiac told me that it was absolutely critical
要帮莱克斯保密
that I help Lex in complete secrecy.
但我讨厌这样
But I hate it.
我伤害了尼娅
I hurt Nia.
我只想跟她再次和好  但
And all I want is to be close with her again, but...
我必须装作冷漠
I have to be cold.
而且
And...
我害怕自己会变成坏人
I'm terrified that I'm becoming the bad guy.
你必须恨我
You must hate me.
你说得对
You're right.
我应该恨你
I should hate you.
但
But...
一切都顺利  所以
everything worked out, so...
我想我是不恨你
I guess I don't.
事实上
In fact...
某种程度上  你算是帮了我
In a way, you kinda helped me.
从小到大  我一直被父亲的罪行所困扰
Growing up, I was constantly burdened by my father's crimes.
你知道  一个疯子的儿子
You know, son of a madman.
显然每个人都因此批评我
Pretty sure everybody judged me for it.
我这辈子所做的一切都是为了反抗这个
Everything I've done in my life has been in defiance of that.
加入超级朋友
Joining the super friends,
和军团成员一起去未来
running out to the future with Legionnaires to
和你的表弟战斗  阻止他
fight your cousin and stop him.
但所有这些
But all that kinda...
都比不上
pales in comparison to
拯救我自己的未来
saving my own future.
另外  我还见到了一些老朋友
Plus, I got to see some old friends.
你还把我当成
You still consider me a...
一个老朋友吗
an old friend?
是的
Yes,
布莱尼  是的
Brainy. I do.
糟糕
Oh, shoot.
我迟到了  你确定你不想来吗
I'm running late. Uh, you sure you don't wanna come?
我有工作要做
I have work to do.
拿起来
Pick it up.
按下按钮
Press the button.
现在  想着你想要的东西
Now, think of what you want.
Q波
Q-waves.
正如我保证过的
As promised.
它们确实存在于这个地球
They do exist on this Earth.
我们只需要把它们带到这个时代
All we had to do was bring them to this time.
生日快乐  圣诞快乐  新年快乐  妹妹
Happy birthday, Christmas, and New Year, little sis.
谢谢你今天去找安德里亚
Thank you for going to Andrea today.
搭档不就这样吗
What are partners for?
要是妈妈能看到我们现在的愉快合作就好了
If only Mother could see how nicely we're playing together now.
别毁了我们的好运气
Let's not ruin the streak.
我不知道她是什么做到的  她绝对作弊了
I don't know how she's doing it, but she's cheating.
-查看她的袖子  我看见了什么  -等等
- Check her sleeves. I saw something. - Wait.
这才是我们的姑娘  她开心多了
Aw, there's our girl. She's feeling better.
但  这次是真的
But, like, for real this time.
比你在迭迭乐上厉害多了
A lot better than you at Jenga.
好了  别说了  因为接下来该我了
Okay, well, wait, 'cause it's my turn now.
准备  开始
Ready, set...
-她要输  -开始
- She's terrible. - Go!
她要输
She's terrible.
兄弟
Dude!
关键就是不让塔倒  我错了吗
The point is for the tower not to fall, am I wrong?
马蒂  你在大都会就是这样玩的吗
Marty, is this how you play in Metropolis?
-不是  -你戴眼镜好看
- No! - Love your glasses, by the way.
谢谢  这是我的习惯
Thank you! These, they're prescription.
是的  规则是那样的  但
Yes. And those are the rules, but,
我们的规则是  如果塔倒了  我们就喝一杯
uh, we play that if it falls, we take a shot,
所以我就...
so I'm just gonna...
等等等  举杯  举杯
Wait, wait, wait. A toast, a toast.
敬新朋友
To new friends.
欢迎
Welcome.
敬老朋友  愿他们总能回到我们身边
And to old friends. May they always find their way back to us.
干杯
Cheers!
这是玩具人最后一个证物
That's the last of Toyman's evidence.
我们把它锁起来吧
Let's lock it up for the night.
我们一决胜负吧
Let's play to win!